As you all know, as per Mr.
Neeraj's comment, we shared with you information about Aditya Birla
Sun Life Insurance Company Limited's Vision
Life Secure Plan. The
thumbnail of the video in which this information was given is at the top of your screen.
If you watch this video, you will understand the eligibility criteria of this plan along with the
maturity benefit, death benefit and bonus. To
save your time, the link to the video has been given in the description of today's video. So, on this
note, please like the video and do
n't forget to share it. Hello everyone, a very warm
welcome to all of you. You are watching You The
Real. I am your own personal advisor
Amitraj Sharma. So, if you have Aditya
Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited's
Vision Life Secure Plan and you have
paid the premium on time for the first two years
and after that you are
unable to pay the premium in future or say that you do
not want to pay the premium further, then in
such a situation you have three options. The
first is to surrender the policy and
take the surrender value, which incurs a
loss.  You know the second
option is to leave the policy under the paid up policy benefit. Now what will happen in the paid up policy benefit, the maturity benefit will also remain, the health benefit will also remain and the whole life cover will also remain. We will understand how later. The third option is that you can take a loan.
Now you know that in a loan,
you have to pay interest on it. So first of all,
we will take an example here so that we can
understand the surrender value of Vision Life Secure Plan of Aditya Birla Sal Life Insurance Company Limited. Let us assume that
Mr. A is 35 years old and
he has taken a sum assured of ₹1 lakh and a
policy term of 25 years. That means the
premium payment term is for the same number of years as the policy term. In this plan, the
premium payment term becomes 25 years for the
sum assured of ₹2500000 annually, that is, 4.3 times we will get
5 lakhs and we will multiply it by five to show that if the
premium has been paid for 5 years, then the amount will be the
regular bonus.  ₹ 7500.
Okay, now we will find out here what the total paid
allied premium is. If
we multiply 22870 by five, then the
total paid allied premium becomes 9350. The
plan says that to calculate the guaranteed surrender value,
you have to multiply the guaranteed surrender
value factor for premium with the
total paid allied premium. Then
you have to add the guaranteed surrender
value factor to it and get the value of the award bonus. As per
our
example, here the
surrender value factor for the pay premium is 50%,
so we will
calculate 50% for 1293. The
surrender value factor for the bonus is 2% and the
award bonus is 17500. We will calculate 2% for it. If we
add both, then we will
get the guaranteed surrender value of 6682 here and the plan will be closed. Now the question
comes that what is the table of surrender value factor,
it is on your screen. The
complete PDF is on your
screen in this plan.  Simple
reversionary bonus is called regular bonus.
Okay, so we had taken a policy term of 25 years.
We had completed 5 years here,
so our guaranteed
surrender value factor of 2% is coming here for the
regular bonus. Okay, and we have given the link of the T Gra channel
in the description of the video,
you can download the PDF from there.
Let us now learn about the
paid-up benefits of Aditya Billa Sunlife Vision Life Secure Plan. We will
take the same example so that we can understand the difference,
how much loss there is in surrendering and
what is the benefit in doing it in a paid-up policy. The same
5-year I am sorry, a sum of Rs 5 lakh and an
age of 35 years, we are taking the same example
and assuming that we have paid the premium continuously for 5 years,
now we are
not able to pay the future premium and
we have left the policy in paid-up policy.
Under the paid-up policy benefit,
okay, then our award bonus will also be the same as
we have just calculated.
We have written the AR regular bonus here,
AR bonus which is Rs. 107000. Now see, we have paid the
premium for 5 years, right? So
what is our number of payable premium here? It is
five. If the policy term was 25 years, then
what will be our number of payable premium? It will be
25 because we are
paying the premium here annually. Why am I
telling this because to find the paid up value factor,
we divide the number of premiums paid by the number of payable premiums. So,
we divided 5 by 25 and
our paid factor came out to be 0.2. Okay,
now here, if during the policy term,
because the policy term is 25 years,
if Mr. A dies during that time under the
paid up policy, then in such a case, the plan says
that the benefit will be reduced by the
paid up sum sum, that is,
we will multiply the paid factor by
0.2 in the sum sum of ₹ lakh and add the AR bonus to it,
which is  If the sum assured is ₹
17,500, then the death benefit will be ₹
7,500. His nominee will get it and the
policy will be closed. If death occurs within the policy
term of 25 years and
25 years have been completed, then the paid-up
maturity benefit will be received. The same is the
reduced paid-up sum and the awarded bonus. If
we multiply ₹5 lakh by 0.2 and
add ₹17,500, then the paid-up
maturity benefit will be ₹27,500. If you have
seen the previous part, then you know that
in this plan, the cover remains till the age of 100 years, that is,
after the completion of 25 years, the life cover will remain in place. What will that be? The
reduced paid-up sum will be ₹5
lakh. If you multiply 0.2 by ₹1 lakh, then
his cover of ₹1 lakh will remain
till the age of 100. So, in this way, you calculate the
paid-up benefit within the paid-up value factor.  Yes, it's
okay, and when the
policy gets converted into a paid-up policy
and you have taken a rider, then its
benefits are stopped and you do
n't get any bonus in the future. Okay, I hope this
information is clear to you. If
you still have any questions,
you can ask in the comment section. Thank you very much for patiently
watching the video till the end. Many thanks,
many thanks. Understand one thing yourself and
explain it to others as well that insurance is
a protection. Protection is never
taken incompletely. No matter how good a plan may seem, one should never
take a plan without reading the policy document. If you have
any other suggestions, if you want something, please do
comment in the comment section
because every video comes
according to you. Thank you. Take care of all of you.